<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: freelancing | Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://loicginoux.github.io/blog/categories/freelancing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://loicginoux.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-27T12:12:28+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://loicginoux.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Loïc Ginoux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sign a pdf contract on mac in 30 seconds]]></title>
    <link href="http://loicginoux.github.io/blog/2014/02/27/sign-a-pdf-contract-on-mac-in-30-seconds/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-27T10:17:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://loicginoux.github.io/blog/2014/02/27/sign-a-pdf-contract-on-mac-in-30-seconds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How did I miss this for so long? I finally found the easiest and free way to sign pdf contract on mac with Preview. It will only require a webcam.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>These are the steps:</p>

<ol>
<li>Open your document with Preview.</li>
<li>Go to Tools > Annotate > Signature</li>
<li>Click on &ldquo;Create Signature from FaceTime camera&rdquo;</li>
<li>Put in front of your camera a white paper with your signature. When you signature get recognized, accept it.</li>
<li>Click anywhere on your document to add the signature.</li>
<li>That&rsquo;s it! Save your document.</li>
<li>Your signature will be registered in Preview for the next contract</li>
</ol>


<p>Wasn&rsquo;t that easy?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joining the greaaat network]]></title>
    <link href="http://loicginoux.github.io/blog/2014/02/17/joining-the-greaaat-network/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-17T13:35:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://loicginoux.github.io/blog/2014/02/17/joining-the-greaaat-network</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quick note to say that I joined a network of french freelancers called <a href="http://www.greaaat.com">greaaat</a>, and you know what? It looks&hellip;. promising!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>That was exactly the kind of network I was looking for. I think that&rsquo;s a really good idea. As a freelancer you are usually by yourself when you are looking for answers or guidance, and usually Google is your best friend in this case (quit sad isn&rsquo;t it?).</p>

<p>Anyway, this kind of network is good for both clients and freelancers. As a client, you are sure to find a freelancer available and if your project is growing and you need different type of skills you will find that with greaaat. There are all type of skills in the network. As a freelancer,  you can find and share all type of resources or questions. We also share our clients. When you get contacted for a work you cannot do, there will be a freelancer in greaaat available and the same goes the other way too when you get a period without much work.</p>

<p>The creator of the network, <a href="http://jonathanpath.com/">Jonathan Path</a>, has good ideas of other websites to help freelancers and I will be happy to help if I can. That means that I will probably write few blog post about freelancing on its website. We will see what come next but I feel like it&rsquo;s a beginning of a new adventure :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
